American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIc. 1826-1836 APS.Archives.IIc APS.Archives.IIc
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], May 10, 1835; 8-1/2x7-1/2; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wilken. 1p.and end. In French. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 13, 1835; 9-1/2x8; Agricultural & Horticultural Society of India
    Calcutta, L.S.: W. Moluck. 4p. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the president of the American philosophical society, May 15, 1835; 8" x 13"; Saltonstall, Rosewell
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add. "Duplicate" Relative to the problem of squaring the circle.
  - Jno. Wickham to Ch[arles] D. Meigs, May 21, 1835; 7 3/4" x 9 15/16"; Wickham, John, 1763-1839
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Richmond, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the A.P.S. Encloses $10 admission fee.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., May 23, 1835; 9x7-1/2; Zoological Society of London
  - Letter to the [A.P.S.], May, 1835; 10x8; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: Wilken. 1p. and end. In Latin. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the APS, June 8, 1835; 9-1/2x8; London Institution
    L.S.: William Tite. 1p. and end. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to the President of the APS, Philadelphia, June 10, 1835; 13x8; Société des antiquaires de France
    Paris, L.S.: Bollièl. 1p. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, 1835 June 16; American Antiquarian Society
    Regarding forwaded publications from the A.P.S..
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 19, 1835; 10x8; Tidyman, Philip
    Bristol, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards donation.
  - J[oel] R. Poinsett to John Vaughan, June 25, 1835; 8 1/4" x 10"; Poinsett, Joel Roberts, 1779-1851
    Bethlem [sic], 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Bishop Anders, who wishes to see the Mexican antiquities and minerals in possession of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the President of the APS, June 30, 1835; 12-1/2x8; Société de géographie (France)
    Paris, L.S.: Roux de Rochelle. 2p. and end. In French. Forwards publication.
  - W[illia]m Vaughan to John Vaughan, July 4, 1835; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p. and address. L.S. With regard to various book exchanges.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, July 11, 1835; 12-1/2x8; Royal Asiatic Society of Great Britain and Ireland
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: H.Harkness. 1p.and add.in care of W.Vaughan, end. Thanks for publications.
  - Report of committee on [John] Gummere's paper on eclipse, July 17, 1835; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: A.D.Bache and Ed.H. Courtenay. 1p. and end. Cf. Minutes, p. 673. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., III, 467 ff.
  - Letter to the President of the APS, Philadelphia, July 25, 1835; 10x8; Société philotechnique
    Paris, L.S.: B[ar]on de Ladoucette. 1p. and end. In French. ----Copy. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, July 31, 1835; 10x8; Worcester, Joseph E. (Joseph Emerson), 1784-1865
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Donates volume.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug. 5, 1835; 8x5; Linnean Society of London
    London, A.L.S.: David Don. 1p.and add.,end.and end. Asks for missing publication.
  - Cha[rle]s Cramer to John Vaughan, Aug. 15, 1835; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Cramer, Charles
    Secretary of A.P.S., New York, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Has forwarded Vaughan's letter of the 9th. to Imperial Acad. of Sciences of St. Petersburg. Sends Annals of Lyceum, III, nos. 1 and 2, to Baron Ferussac.
  - Cha[rle]s Cramer to John Vaughan, Aug. 18, 1835; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Cramer, Charles
    Secretary of A.P.S., New York, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Sends Annals of Lyceum, III, nos. 1 and 2, to Vaughan. Statement as to volumes of A.P.S. Transactions in possession of Lyceum.
  - Letter to John vaughan, Philadelphia, Aug. 18, 1835; 5x8; Academia Real das Sciencias de Lisboa
    Lisbon, A.L.S.: Antonio Joaquin Moreni. 2p.and add. In Portuguese. In English there is a note from Joseph Joachim Emeryaldo to Thomas Tolentino da Silva to deliver this letter to J.Vaughan. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to John K. Kane, Aug. 26, 1835; 9x7-1/2; Academia Real das Sciencias de Lisboa
    Lisbon, L.S.: Macedo. 4p.and end. In French. Forwards publications. Sends a list of volumes published.
  - Letter to John K. Kane, Philadelphia, Aug. 26, 1835; 9x7-1/2; Academia Real das Sciencias de Lisboa
    Lisbon, L.S.: Macedo. 1p.and end. In French. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Sept. 1, 1835; 10x8; Nagy, Károly, 1797-1868
    Vienna, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Donates volume.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, secretary of Philosophical society, Sept. 1, Sept. 13, 1835; 8" x 10"; Jackson, Julian R., 1790-1853
    St. Petersburg, A.L.S. 3p. Presents copy of his "Aide memoire du voyageur"; also his "Essay on lakes," forwarded by Mr. Buchanan. Comments on travel books of the day. Mentions Mr. Middleton.
  - Statement of the height of the thermometer and course of the winds at Fort Union.., Setember 1, 1835 -June 27, 18361 Sept. to 27 June, 1835 to 1836; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Hamilton, C. J. A.
    from t.p., 12 pp. Com. Presented to A.P.S.: November 4, 1836. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 693.
  - Cha[rle]s Cramer to John Vaughan, Sep. 10, 1835; 7 7/8" x 10"; Cramer, Charles
    Secretary of A.P.S., New York, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Regarding transmission of Annals of Lyceum, III, nos. 1 and 2. Erection of new building for Lyceum of Natural History in New York.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 11, 1835; 5" x 8"; Philadelphia. Select and common council
    Philadelphia, Printed L. 1p. and end. Invitation to attend the eulogium on the Hon. John Marshall, to be pronounced by Horace Binney. Cf. Minutes, Sept. 18, 1835.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 15, 1835; 9x7; Rich, O.
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S. 2p. Business.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 24, 1835; 10x8-1/4; Rönne, Friedrich Ludwig v., 1795-1865
    Hoboken, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Informs him that a package of APS publications, destined for Germany, has been lost.
  - W[illiam] C. Rives to P[eter] S. DuPonceau and others, September 25, 1835; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Rives, William C. (William Cabell), 1793-1868
    Castle Hill, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Regrets that he must decline invitation to dinner to be given in honor of Dr. Robert M. Patterson.
  - Robley Dunglison to P[eter] S. DuPonceau and others, September 30, 1835; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Dunglison, Robley, 1798-1869
    Baltimore, 1 p. A.L.S Regrets that he must decline invitation to dinner to be given in honor of Dr. Robert M. Patterson.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Oct. 1, 1835; 9x8; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    A.L.S. 2p. and add. Wishes to write Société asiatique about back issues of their publications. On same sheet with copy of letter from the société asiatique to the Sec.of the APS; June 9, 1832.
  - Letter to P.S. DuPonceau, [1835] October 3; Garibaldi, Giuseppe, 1807-1882
    Garibaldi presents to the A.P.S. a volume of the Transactions of the Royal accademia delle scienze of Turin.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Oct. 5, 1835; 10x7-1/2; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, L.S. 2p. and add. Forwards publications.of the Royal society.
  - Letter to W[illia]m Vaughan, Oct. 7, 1835; 9x7-1/2; Great Britain. Public Record Office
    L.S.: C. P. Cooper. 1p. Thanks for APS publications.
  - Peter S. DuPonceau to John Vaughan, October 20, 1835; 7 15/16" x 9 15/16"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Concerning Ippolito Rosellini's work on Egyptian antiquities. Is "Very anxious" that the Society possess it.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Oct. 20, 1835; 10x7-1/2; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    A.L.S. 3p. and add. Forwards publications. Contains also note from P.Vaughan to J.Vaughan; Oct. 26, 1835.
  - D. B. Warden to John Vaughan, October 20, 1835; 4 1/2" x 7"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Has distributed vol. VI, pt. 1, A.P.S. Transactions.
  - R. Eglesfeld Griffith to John Vaughan, October 22, 1835; 7 3/4" x 9 15/16"; Griffith, R. Eglesfeld (Robert Eglesfeld), 1798-1850
    Treasurer of the A.P.S., ----, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.N.S. Note of resignation from curatorship of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the president of the American philosophical society, Oct. 27, 1835; 8" x 10"; Philadelphia. Select and common council. Committee on city property.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S: Richd. Price, chairman. 1p. and add. (addressed to Alex. Dallas Bache) Inquires on what terms the Society's hall could be obtained for the use of city offices. Cf. Minutes, Nov. 6, 1835.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Oct., 1835; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: Erman. 1p.and add. In Latin.
  - D. B. Warden to John Vaughan, November 1, 1835; 4 5/8" x 7 1/8"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Has offered his American library to the government of Virginia.
  - Report of committee on [E.H.] Courtenay's paper on longitude, Nov. 6, 1835; 8x6-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: A.D.Bache and R.M.Patterson. 1p. and end. Cf. Minutes, p.677. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., V, 343 ff.
  - Report of the committee on lighting the hall with gas, November 6, 1835; 6 3/8" x 7 1/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S.: R[obert] M. Patterson. Have authorized the introduction of the pipes.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, [1835] November 12; Lee, Richard Henry, 1794-1865
    Forwards manuscript.
  - Letter to the secretary of the American philosophical society, Nov. 19, 1835; 8" x 9 1/2"
    London, Printed L.S.: Chas. Konig, For. Sec. R.S. 1p. Announcement of medals to be awarded in 1838.
  - Charles C. Rafn to the Secretary of the A.P.S., November 19, 1835; 8" x 9 7/8"; Rafn, Carl Christian, 1795-1864
    Copenhagen, 2 pp., address and endorsement. L.S. Concerning the near completion of the work, Antiquitates Americanae, announced by the Royal Society of Northern Antiquaries.
  - Prospectus:, November 19, 1835; 5 1/8" x 8 3/8"; Kongelige Nordiske oldskriftselskab (Denmark)
    Antiquitates Americanae and Antiquitates Britannicae et Hibernicae, Copenhagen, 11 pp. Pr.D. Enclosed in: C. C. Rafn to the Secretary of the A.P.S., November 19, 1835.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Nov. 21, 1835; 10x7-1/2; Tanner, Henry Schenck, 1786-1858
    A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Enclosure of list of maps for sale. Offers maps to the society. With this is a receipt from A. Peries to the A.P.S.; Nov. 30, 1835.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Nov. 24, 1835; 8x5; Coxe, John Redman, 1773-1864
    A.L.S. 1p.and add., end. Will not pay any more to the society.
  - [Baron de] Ferussac to [John] Vaughan, November 24, 1835; 7 1/2" x 9 1/4"; Ferussac, Baron de. L-4
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French.) Acknowledges receipt of bill of exchange for 110 francs. Will forward designated works to the A.P.S.
  - Receipt to the American philosophical society for maps purchased, Nov. 30, 1835; 4x7; Peries, A.
    A.D.S. 1p. With letter from H.S.Tanner to J. Vaughan; Nov. 21, 1835.
  - Report... Philadelphia, December 2, 1835; 7 15/16" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society. Committee on publications
    2 pp. D.S.: Isaac Lea, R[obert] Eglesfeld Griffith, Isaac Hays. Status of publications ordered by the Society; finances of the committee.
  - A[aron] Bancroft to John Vaughan, December 4, 1835; 7 5/8" x 9 7/8"; Bancroft, Aaron, 1755-1839
    Librarian of A.P.S., Worcester, [Mass.], 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Death of Mr. Bal[d]win, librarian of the American Antiquarian Society. Exchange of duplicates with the A.P.S.
  - Société de Géographie to the President of the Philosophical Society of Philadelphia (sic), December 8, 1835; 8 7/8" x 13 3/8"; Société de géographie (France)
    Paris, 1p. and endorsement. L.S.: Roux de Rochelle. (In French.) Forwards Bulletin of Société de Géographie to the A.P.S.
  - Report of committee of finance and accounts on the treasurer's [John Vaughan] accounts, Dec. 18, 1835; 8x6-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Clement C. Biddle and Roberts Vaux. 1p.
  - Report of committee on Dudley's tables for calculating the moon's place, Dec. 19, 1835; 8x6-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: A.D.Bache, Edward H. Courtenay and R.M. Patterson. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.678.
  - Report... upon a paper entitled "Theory of Rain,", December 26, 1835; 7 13/16" x 9 13/16"; American Philosophical Society. Board of officers
    by "Investigator," submitted for the Extra-Magellanic premium, [Philadelphia], 7pp. and endorsement. D. Recommend paper for the award.
  - Peter S. DuPonceau to J[ohn] Vaughan, December 27, 1835; 6 3/8" x 8 1/8"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    [Philadelphia], A.L.S. Concerning Dr. [Nathaniel] Chapman's intention of leaving his library to the A.P.S.
  - G[eorge] Ord to John Vaughan, December 29, 1835; 7 13/16" x 9 13/16"; Ord, George, 1781-1866
    Doylestown, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Hopes that Robert M. Patterson will take his place as vice-president of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Jan. 13, 1836; 10x8; Dannery, S.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. In French. Presents volumes.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Jan. 13, 1836; 13x8; Dannery, S.
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. In French. Forwards boxes.
  - Note to John Vaughan, Jan. 21, 1836; 2-1/2x7-1/2; Cramer, Charles
    New York, A.N.S. 1p.and end. Asks for payment for publication.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Jan. 27, 1836; 6x5-1/2; Bache, Franklin, 1792-1864
    A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards volume.which is being returned to the Library.
  - Nathan Dunn to Alex[ander] Dallas Bache, January 28, 1836; 8" x 10"; Dunn, Nathan, 1782-1844
    Philadelphia, 1 p. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of his certificate of membership in the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 1, 1836; 10x8; Coleman, Edward, 1765-1839
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to J[ohn] K[intzing] Kane, Philadelphia, Feb. 6, 1836; 10x8; Asiatic Society of Bengal
    Calcutta, L.S.: J. Prinsep. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publications.
  - J. H. Alexander to J[ohn] Vaughan, February 12, 1836; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Alexander, J. H. (John Henry), 1812-1867
    Baltimore, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Enclosing copies of the reports of this year on the new map of Maryland.
  - List of books deposited with the A.P.S., Feb. 19, 1836; 9x7-1/2; Brown, John Porter, 1814-1872
    A.D. 1p., end.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 20, 1836; 10x8; Royal Society of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Chas.Konig. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Feb. 23, 1836; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Académie royale des sciences, des lettres et des beaux-arts de Belgique
    Brussels, L.S.: Quetelet. 2p. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Account of John Vaughan with the American philosophical society, Feb. 25-Dec. 16, 1836; 10x7-1/2; Snider, Jacob
    D.S. 1p.and end.
  - Minority report... against recommending "Investigator's" paper for the Extra-Magellanic premium, March 4, 1836; 7 7/8" x 9 1/16"; American Philosophical Society. Board of officers
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: James Mease, William Hembel, E[ugenius] Nulty.
  - Letter to the president of the A.P.S., March 4, 1836; 8x6; Nulty, Eugenius
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. Cf. Minutes, p.682.
  - Redmond Conyngham to John Vaughan, March 5, 1836; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Conyngham, Redmond, 1781-1846
    Lancaster, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Asks Mr. Vaughan to locate certain material in the files of the A.P.S. that would help him in his study of the early history of Lancaster.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 16, 1836; 10x8; Royal Irish Academy
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Jos. H. Singer. 1p.and add.,end. Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Philadelphia, March 24, 1836; 10x7-1/2; Randolph, William B.
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Forwards memoirs etc. of T.Jefferson. FILM 199 FRAME 423
  - Letter to the Secretary of the APS, March 24, 1836; 9-1/2x8; Society for the Encouragement of Arts, Manufactures, and Commerce (Great Britain)
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 27, 1836; 10x8; Palfrey, John Gorham, 1796-1881
    Ohio River, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Forwards material, including the "pedigree of Franklin." FILM54-64 FRAME 100
  - Letter to the librarian of the A.P.S., March 28, 1836; 10x8; Mirror of Parliament
    Printed L. filled in in ms. 2p.and add. Asks for subscription from the APS.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, March 30, 1836; 10x8; Morelli, Chevalier Domenico de
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Donates volume.
  - Report of committee on Dr. Hare's papers, April 1, 1836; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Franklin Bache, Geo. B. Wood, and Henry D. Rogers. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.684. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., V, 347 ff.
  - Jos[eph] Hopkinson to John Vaughan, April 1, 1836; 8" x 10"; Hopkinson, Joseph, 1770-1842
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S. an electrical Battery once the property of Benjamin Franklin. FILM54-61 FRAME131
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 1, 1836; 10x8; Kane, John K. (John Kintzing), 1795-1858
    A.L.S. 1p. Forwards publications.
  - Charles Rümker to J[oh]n Vaughan, April 3, 1836; 5" x 8 1/8"; Rümker, Carl, 1788-1862
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Hamburg, 5pp. and address. A.Com.S. Forwards his calculations of American observations of the solar eclipse of May 15, 1836.
  - W. J. Duane to John Vaughan, April 5, 1836; 5 1/8" x 8 1/8"; Duane, William J. (William John), 1780-1865
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Offers to sell two books from his father's library to the A.P.S. for $3.50.
  - Letter to James Mease, Philadelphia, April 6, 1836; 9x7-1/2; Great Britain. Public Record Office
    L.S.: C. P. Cooper. 1p.and add. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 14, 1836; 9x7; Pedersen, Peder, 1774-1851
    Copenhagen, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Forwards publications from the king of Denmark.
  - Report of committee on paper on tornadoes by A.D.Bache, April 15, 1836; 9x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: R.M. Patterson, J.P.Espy and G. Emerson. 1p.pnd end. Cf. Minutes, p.685. Printed: Trans., n.s., vol. V, 407 ff.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., April 16, 1836; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Agricultural & Horticultural Society of India
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John Bell. 1p. Wishes to exchange seeds.
  - Particulars of the New Brunswick tornado, 1836 April 23; Janeway, J. J. (Jacob Jones), 1774-1858
    See Proceedings, XXII, Pt. 3, 687.
  - D. B. Warden to John Vaughan, April 28, 1836; 6 7/8" x 8 7/8"; Warden, David Bailie, 1772-1845
    Librarian of A.P.S., Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. With regard to various parcels he has forwarded. Is pleased with renewal of friendly relations between France and the United States.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 1, 1836; 10x8; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Wilken. 1p.and end. In German. Thanks for publications.
  - Report of committee on [J.P.] Espy's paper on tornadoes, May 6, 1836; 3x6-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: A.D.Bache and R.M.Patterson. 1p. Cf. Minutes, p. 685. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., V, 421 ff.
  - Letter to L. Woodbury, May 17, 1836; 10x8; United States. Dept. of the Treasury
    L.S.: Jno. Laub. 1p. Copy. Books sent as presents to the APS are duty free.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, May 17, 1836; 9-1/2x8; Wael, Emilius de
    New York, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Forwarded publications to Quetelet.
  - Letter to John Forsyth, May 18, 1836; 10x8; United States. Dept. of the Treasury
    L.S.: Levi Woodbury. 1p.and end. Answers Vaughan's inquiry if gifts of books to the APS are subject to duty. See also: U.S. Treasury department to L. Woodbury; May 17, 1836.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, 1836 May 18; Quadrada, F. de P.
    Quadrada informs John Vaughan of the deaths of Don Joseph Miguel de Flores and Don Luis de Urbina.
  - Report of committee on Bache's and Courtenay's paper on magnetism, May 20, 1836; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: R.M.Patterson, Isaiah Lukens and James P. Espy. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.686. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., V, 427 ff.
  - Letter to P.S. Du Ponceau, May 31, 1836; 8" x 13"; Gálvez, Mariano, 1794-1862
    Guatemala, Translation of L. (by P.S. Du Ponceau) 2p. Exchange of correspondence between learned societies. Donations, including ms. grammars of Indian languages. Further communication from Juan Antonio de Asmitia. Contains also translations of the following letters: M. Galvez to P.S. Du Ponceau; July 5,1836 Pedro Molina to M. Galvez; June 16, 1836 Juan A. de Azmitia to P.S.D.; June 1, 1836 List of mss. sent to P.S.D. by Galvez, July 5, 1836 List of printed books and papers. Cf. Minutes Sept. 16, 1836.
  - Letter to [the A.P.S.], May, 1836; 9-1/2x8; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
  - Letter to P.S. D[u Ponceau], June 1, 1836; Azmitia, Juan Antonio? De
    Guatemala, Translation of L. (by P.S. Du Ponceau) portion of 1p. On same sheet with letter from M. Galvez to Du Ponceau, May 31,1836. Will supply information about Guatemala.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, June 13, 1836; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and add.,end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June13, 1836; 6-1/2x4; White, William, 1748-1836
    A.L.S. 1p. and add.and end. Forwards publications.
  - Receipt to J[ohn] Vaughan for payment of charges on books in New York, June 15, 1836; 8x5; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, A.D.S. 1p.and end.
  - Letter to John K. Kane, Philadelphia, June 16, 1836; 9x7-1/2; Academia Real das Sciencias de Lisboa
    Lisbon, L.S.: Macedo. 1p.and end. In French. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to [Mariano] Galvez, June 16, 1836; Molina, Pedro, 1777-1854
    Guatemala, Translation of L. (by P.S. Du Ponceau) Portion of 1p. On same sheet with letter from M. Galvez to Du Ponceau, May 31, 1836. Manuscripts relative to the aboriginal Indian languages. P.S. Du Ponceau to be proposed for membership in the Academy of sciences.
  - Letter to Peter DuPonceau, Philadelphia, June 16, 1836; 10x8; Imperatorskai︠a︡ akademīi︠a︡ nauk i khudozhestv (Russia)
    St. Petersbourg, L.S.: Pierre de Goetz. 2p. and end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Report of committee on Dr. Hare's paper, June 17, 1836; 9-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Franklin Bache and Geo.B. Wood. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.687. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., V, 399 ff.
  - Report of committee on Mr. Thornton's paper on polygons, June 17, 1836; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: A.D.Bache, R.M.Patterson and Edward H. Courtenay. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.687. For paper see Ms.Comm.to the APS: Math. and Astronomy, v.2, no.119.
  - Nicholas Carlisle to John K. Kane, June 17, 1836; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Carlisle, Nicholas, 1771-1847
    London, 1 p. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to John K. Kane, June 17, 1836; 10x8; Society of Antiquaries of London
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Nich. Carlisle. 1p.and end. Thanks for publication.